NEW YORK STATE CONFERENCE OF LOCAL MENTAL HYGIENE DIRECTORS RECORDS (APAP315) 1950-2009
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Records 1950-2009
nam_apap315
36.5
New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The records of the New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors trace the development of mental healthcare throughout the state from the early 1950s through the beginning of the twenty-first century. Established in the mid-1970s, the Conference's records include correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, reports, and manuals that chronicle the efforts of mental health professionals as they encourage local, county, and state agencies to provide quality, affordable services for persons living with mental illness, chemical dependency, and/or developmental disability.
Access
Access to this record group is mainly unrestricted; the exceptions are folders 20 through 26 in Series 5, Box 2. Researchers seeking access to this material should contact the head of archives.
Red asterisks (***) denote restricted items.
Acquisition Information
All items in the New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Records were donated by the Conference to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in 2009.
Organizational Sketch
The New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors (NYSCLMHD) specializes in advocacy for the mentally ill, the developmentally disabled, and/or people with chemical dependencies. The Conference also extends outreach efforts to the families of those they serve. Its efforts focus on ensuring that people with various mental health needs have quality, affordable care, guiding formation of local and state policies to make sure that they are as current and relevant as possible. [1]
The NYSCLMHD was formed in 1976 under Article 41 of the state Mental Hygiene Law, which covers local and unified services. Article 41 was “designed to enable and encourage local governments to develop in the community preventive, rehabilitative, and treatment services offering continuity of care” and stresses the need for cooperation among local, county, and state governments in order to provide the best level of mental healthcare. [2] As such, the Conference— operating at the county level—serves as a link between statewide and local services, confirming that policies are carried out efficiently in the realms of clinical and rehabilitative work. The Conference opened its Albany, New York headquarters in 1978, and as an affiliate of the New York State Association of Counties (NYSAC), it was originally located in the NYSAC building on State Street. [3] The Conference continues to be affiliated with NYSAC but has since moved to a different building in downtown Albany.
The NYSCLMHD, which is a not-for-profit organization, oversees a complex and extensive network of professionals, requiring participation by mental health directors and commissioners from New York State’s 57 counties and New York City*. [4] These are the people who are already coordinating mental health care services in their own counties and therefore have the knowledge and background to correlate services between local, county, and state agencies. Over the years they have worked closely with the New York State Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities, Office of Mental Health, Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse, and Division of Substance Abuse as they analyze the state’s mental healthcare system and make recommendations for improvement. Daily operations are overseen by the Conference’s executive director, who in turn reports to the executive committee and chairperson. The executive committee, which meets monthly, is made up of past and present committee chairpersons, current officers, and regional representatives. All members meet twice a year at conferences, and officers are elected for two-year terms, as per the Conference’s bylaws. [5]
The Conference has devoted itself to a vast number of projects since its inception in the mid-1970s. A sample of its work includes children’s mental welfare, adult housing needs, affordable services, and care of the mentally ill during and after prison sentences. Over the years, members have both sponsored and attended many workshops and conferences designed to enhance the skills of those working on behalf of the mentally ill, chemically dependent, and developmentally disabled. It also continues to focus effort on bringing greater understanding of mental health issues to the general public as well as to key professions, such as law enforcement and education, so that people with special needs can be more efficiently integrated into everyday life.
*New York State officially has 62 counties; New York City’s five boroughs are each considered to be a separate county. (See www.nysegov.com)
[1] New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors, Inc. “About Us.” Accessed 18 January 2011 from http://www.clmhd.org/aboutus.aspx.
[2] Justia US Law. “2006 New York Code: Declaration of Purpose. Article 41.01.” Accessed 28 February 2011 from http://law.justia.com/newyork/codes/2006/mental-hygiene/mhy041.01_41.01.html.
[3] Background information on Conference's formation/early days, Series 1 Administrative, Box 1, Folder 7 New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Records, 1950-2008. M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York.
[4] New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors, Inc. Home page. Accessed 15 February 2011 from http://www.clmhd.org.
[5] Background information on Conference's formation/early days, Series 1 Administrative, Box 1, Folder 7 New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Records, 1950-2008. M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors (NYSCLMHD) contain meeting minutes, correspondence, reports, and newsletters documenting the founding and day-to-day activities of the group, including original by-laws and articles of incorporation. There are also records of many of the NYSCLMHD’s specific projects from the late 1970s through the early 2000s, such as managed care/Medicaid/special needs plans, grant applications, juvenile care issues, housing concerns, partnerships with other organizations, disaster preparedness, and care of mental needs patients in prison.
Researchers will also find some materials on the history of mental health care in the state of New York. In addition, there are documents pertaining to mental health professionals’ increased efforts to partner with law enforcement to achieve better understanding of those living with mental illness, developmental disabilities, or the effects of substance abuse.
In most instances, folder titles have been retained according to the record-keeping habits of the NYSCLMHD.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Administrative Files, 1950-2005, Undated
Series 2 - Chronological Files, 1995-2005, Undated
Series 3 - Office of Legislative and Government Affairs Director, 1991-2003, Undated
Series 4 - County Plans, Operations, and Government, 1980-2009, Undated
Series 5 - Projects and Committees, 1979-2001, Undated
Series 6 - Managed Care and Special Needs Plans, 1991-2000, Undated
Series 7 - Subject Files, 1985-2008, Undated
Series 8 - NYSCLMHD Newsletters, 1980-2008, Undated
Series 9 - Reports and Publications, 1982, 1989-2006, Undated
Most of the series in the New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Records are arranged in alphabetical order. Exceptions are Series #2, Chronological Files, which are in order by date, and Series #8, NYSCLMHD Newsletters, which are also arranged by date.
Subject and Genre Headings
Medicine and Health Care; Dvoskin, Joel; Conference Update; Mental health--United States.; Mental health--Adolescent.; Mental health--New York (State); Substance abuse--Treatment--United States.; Mental illness--Treatment--United States.; Chemical dependency; Developmental disability; Albany (NY); New York (State); Correspondence; Photographs; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Legal documents; Manuals (instructional materials); Minutes; Bills (legislative records); New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors; New York State Association of Counties
Container List
- Administrative Files, 1950-2005; Undated; 1; 1.6
  Arranged alphabetically
  The administrative files contain executive meeting minutes from the Conference’s earliest days through the late 1980s. During those years, members kept the minutes in large, hardcover binders; the archivist removed the papers from those binders for preservation purposes and placed them in acid-free folders in the order in which they appeared in the original binders. In the 1990s, Conference members began filing their meeting minutes under the heading of “chronological files” along with meeting announcements and correspondence. The chronological files became series two of this collection and researchers will find more meeting minutes there. However, there is a gap in the Conference's meeting minutes from 1989-1994.
  This series also contains founding documents such as original charters and by-laws as well as files pertaining to activities of the executive director. Please note that there are several executive committee meeting files in Series #5: Projects and Committees.
  - 340-B Prescription drugs, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Access to child psychiatry, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adult homes, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aid to localities fiscal system: Multi-agency request, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Albany/Rensselaer Housing Taskforce, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual spring meeting, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Background information on conference's formation, early days, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - By-laws binder: By-laws and rosters, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - By-laws binder: Correspondence, finances, and executive committee, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - By-laws binder: Executive committee cont.'d, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Costs of O.M.H. psychiatric hospitals, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - County commissioners' forums, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dual recovery coordinators, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Electronic document management systems workshops, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial management policy revision, 1999-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Financial reports, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Greenlight Program reports, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History of mental health care, 1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Integrated children's service/ TAP issue, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Leadership retreat follow-up, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Medicaid neutrality, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Meeting minutes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Meeting minutes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Meeting minutes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting minutes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Meeting minutes, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Meeting minutes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Meeting minutes, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Meeting minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting minutes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting minutes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting minutes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mental Health Committee minutes, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mental Health Glossary of Programs and Services, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mental Hygiene Services: Partnering at the local level, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NACBHD Fall 2005 conference (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - NYSAC Fall conference-- Health and Mental Health Committee, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - NYS Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors Technical Assistance Project, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities: NYS-OPTS Analysis, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Partnership Committee, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Officers' meetings with commissioners and legislative chairs, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - O.M.H. new initiatives- status update, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Planning meeting with Commissioner Carpinello, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - PROS county role, 2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PROS outcome measures, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PROS provider agreement, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PROS regulations- comments, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sample of Conference brochures, 1999; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Secure facilities, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Standing committee planning and protocols, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - State Association survey, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Telemedicine/telepsychiatry, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tuttle, Alfred: "Purposes of the Organization", Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Chronological Files, 1995-2005; Undated; 2; 12.0 cu. ft.
  Arranged chronologically.
  The name of this series comes right from the Conference’s own record-keeping system. In the 1990s it stopped storing meeting minutes separately in oversized binders and began interfiling them with correspondence, meeting announcements, memorandums, and treasurer’s reports in folders labeled with the current month and year. Minutes include regularly scheduled events, such as executive committee meetings, as well as ad hoc meetings. Memos include those sent by the NYSCLMHD as well as those received by the Conference from outside sources such the New York State Office of Mental Health and the Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse.
  - NYSAC correspondence, 1995 January-1995 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - January, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - February, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - March, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - April, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - May, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - June, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - July, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - August, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - September, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - October, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - November, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - December, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - January, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - February, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - March, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - April, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  - May, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - June, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
  - July, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
  - August, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - September, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - October, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - October, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - November, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - December, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Executive committee meeting minutes, 1997 December-1999 July (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - January, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - February, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - April, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11-15)
  - May, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - June, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - July, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - August, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - September, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - October, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - November, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - December, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Technical assistance correspondence, 1997 May-1998 April (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Welfare-to-Work, 1997 January-1997 December (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Managed care, 1998 February-1998 May (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Medicaid Carveout, 1998 February (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Public benefit corporations, 1996 January-1996 May (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Welfare reform, 1998 April-1998 May (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) information, 1998 March (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - AHLPR grant, 1998 March-1998 April (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1998 Technical Assistance Plan, 1997 November (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - January, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - February, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - March, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
  - April, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - May, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4-7)
  - June, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
  - July, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10-13)
  - August, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - September, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
  - October, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 18-20)
  - November, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - December, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Minutes and treasurer's reports, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - January, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - February, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - March, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - April, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
  - May, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 12-15)
  - June, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 16-18)
  - July, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
  - August, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - September, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - October, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
  - November, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - December, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - January, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
  - February, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - March, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - April, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
  - May, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - June, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - July, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - August, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - September, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - October, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - November, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - December, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - January, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - February, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - March, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - April, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - May, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - June, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
  - July, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
  - August, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - September, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - October, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - November, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - December, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - December, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - January, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - February, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - March, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - April, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - May, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
  - June, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - July, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - August, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - September, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 15-17)
  - October, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - November, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - December, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
  - January, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - February, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
  - March, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - April, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
  - May, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - June, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - July, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - August, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - September, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - October, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
  - November, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - December, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
  - January, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - February, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - March, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
  - April, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
  - May, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - June, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 9-11)
  - July, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - August, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - September, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - October, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
  - November, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - December, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
  - January, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - February, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - March, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - April, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
  - May, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - June, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - July, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - August, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - September, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - October, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - November, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - December, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 17-18)
  - General CLMHD information, Undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Office of Legislative and Government Affairs Director, 1991-2003; Undated; 3; 3.0 cu. ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains information related to state reinvestment plans, Medicaid concerns, managed care, and housing. While materials on all of these topics also can be found in Series 5, 6, and 7, the documents in this series were all kept specifically by the director of legislative and government affairs and therefore remain together in their own series.
  - 1998 Reinvestment extender, 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Community Mental Health Reinvestment Bill letters sent to other organizations requesting support from D. Coughlin, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Community Mental Health Reinvestment Bill press clips, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Community Mental Health Reinvestment Bill press clips, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill of 1992 #2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill of 1992 #3- with lines and brackets, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill of 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill of 1993- Comments, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill testimony, 1992; 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill: Language amendments, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill: Language amendments, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill: Legislation (Drafts), 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill: Legislation (Drafts), 1992; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Bill: Local Medicaid share, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Community Mental Health Resources Trust Fund, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Community Reinvestment Funding 1994-1995, 1994 August 08 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - County mental health Medicaid expenditures (county responses), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - County mental hygiene expenditures, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Developmental Disabilities Services Office feedback, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Grants, 1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - List of support for community mental health resources bill, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Managed care, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Managed care, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Managed care demos under NYSDSS, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Mandate Relief Project, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Medicaid budget bill- Health only, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Medicaid managed care- Articles and reports, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Medicaid managed care- Articles and reports, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Medicaid Managed Care Coalition, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Medicaid managed care- Coalition for Homeless and New York Public Welfare Association, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Members/background, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Membership meetings, NYSCLMHD, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mental health terms and background, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New and expanded programs funded through reinvestment 1994-1995 through 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New York City- Managed special care, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Office of Mental Health 1999 contract agreement and TAP, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Office of Mental Health 1999 contract agreement and TAP, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Office of Mental Health 551 regulations, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Office of Mental Health 551 regulations, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Office of Mental Health: Revisions to Part 592 Comprehensive Outpatient Program, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Office of Mental Health: Reinvestment planning guidelines, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Office of Mental Health: Reinvestment reference charts, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Partnership Committee, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)